

Personal Information

Ramón Roche - Web Developer www.ramonroche.com

Mobile: 858-699-7758 mrpollo@gmail.com

655 6th Avenue Suite 711 San Diego, CA 92101

Summary of Qualifications

I'm a Programmer that seeks an opportunity on a creative position; Over 6 years of experience in the vast world of web development, Experience Managing Teams and crafting projects to perfection.

Profile

I'm a multitasking creative person that likes to solve problems and I believe there is always more than one solution to a problem, I have Excellent presentation and communication skills, I am a very good team member, I have experience working with clients and managing timelines, I'm not easily discouraged by limitations.

Experience

Gobble Communication Group

2010 April - Present - Front End Developer

Agency work has been really interesting so far, working closely with teams overseeing projects meeting with clients and conducting research to better respond to client requirements

Some of my work:

- Installing, Theming Wordpress sites,
- Create, Edit, JSP Pages using the JavaServer Pages Standard Tag Library
- Multiple Javascript Fixes, additions to projects including, Creating a tab based view with cross-browser gradients and round corners, Form Validation, Extensive DOM Manipulation
 - Styled and updated Page Styles using compliant rules
 - Cut templates always using cross-browser markup XHTML Strict and Transitional
 - Facebook Tabs
 - Flash Ads. Flash billboards

X1FM Network

2008 - 2010 - IT Director

My responsibilities as the IT director, varied from Networking to oversee the audio/video production, and the website development, my main goals where to build from scratch a system that could hold to the demand and expand as necessary, I was responsible for the budget and final delivery of the product, we released a new version of the site that will remain the spirit of the service for at least 1 year. The Project includes MySQL Master – Slave setup, 4 load balanced Web Servers, and 2 Streaming origin servers, 2 rsynched Storage servers between remote offices, 2 utility servers for SVN and Monitoring with Nagios and Cacti.

2007 – 2008 - Web Developer

I Joined X1FM moments before I finished my school as a web developer, when I joined I was in charge of all of the Flash development, then I proposed the change to a more easier to manage system under PHP/ MYSQL which was accepted and I lead the project until it was finished.

http://www.x1fm.com/

Mobile: 858-699-7759 - mrpollo@gmail.com 655 6th Avenue Suite 711, San Diego, CA 92101



Esquina Norte

2004 – Present - Logistics

Esquina Norte is the most important Design Conference of the Northwest region of Mexico, is a series of interactive seminars and hands-on training courses that takes place every fall in Tijuana, I have been involved in the project for 5 years working in logistics, preparing schedule's, getting in touch with designers around the world.

http://www.esquinanorte.com/

Boxel Workshops

2009 - Present - Instructor

Preparing professionals and students in the Areas of development, my main focus in the school is to give design students a better understanding of programming skills and the world of development. http://boxelworkshops.com/

Freelance Web Developer

2004 - 2008

I started my career as a web developer working as a freelance agent for local companies on my hometown; rapidly I started to gain more clients on neighbor towns.

Education

CETYS Universidad

Digital Graphic Design Engineering

I have an valid Equivalence Degree for the USA. CETYS is the most prestigious school in the north-west of México, I studied DGDE Digital Graphic Design Engineering, a great education has been given to me in most of the more demanding graphic and development areas such as Video, Audio, Web, 3D, and Print media.

Skills

I master all of the following Programming Languages, Serivces and Software Packages:

JSP

Adobe Master Collection: Adobe Flash Adobe Photoshop Adobe Illustrator Adobe Premier Adobe After Affects LightWave for 3D modeling and animation PHP5 (I MySQL HTML CSS Javascr	- HTML 5 - XHTML Strict - XHTML Trans	Actionscript (1,2,3) Bash Scripting Perl Apache2 Flash Media Server Liquidsoap Icecast Shoutcast FFMPEG	Google Apps Mac Linux Windows
--	---	---	--